one of the things you have to do to be a
technologist is you have to be able to
focus and this is one of the many things
that just listed in preparing mentally
for uh the beginner boost for skill
stack but in general in order to have a
Tech Career if you
cannot
focus then you will fail and there are a
lot of things to to discuss related to
that but I am going to try to just
knock out the the major ways that I
personally have been able to focus and
you can find out how that works for you
um the number one way to to focus and
this is for
learning uh it's for executing on your
job it's for learning as well so it kind
of is a double thing the number one way
of course is to separate yourself from
distractions and this is easy to say
it's hard to do what do I mean by
distractions I mean your family your
dogss um I mean there's some people who
like to you know be right in the middle
of everything it could be you know
sounds around you I actually wear when
I'm really into a session I put earplugs
in I personally this is me personally me
personally I'll put earplugs
in uh I don't know if I have some sort
of neurologically Divergent thing going
on with me but I cannot have extra
sounds what I'm really really focusing
on um you know breaking an algorithm
down particularly if the if the code is
complicated um so that's one of the ways
to focus another thing very oddly I used
to take my laptop to uh a very noisy Pub
or coffee shop and the noisier the
better because it would just all become
white noise and then I could just do my
thing uh some people are like they
really like clickity clack loud
keyboards and I cannot do a loud
keyboard I loud keyboards really really
distract me and I'm unable to focus um
okay so the first way is to remove
distractions whatever those distractions
are for you um and sometimes that might
mean waking up at a different time
during the day and operating during that
time and that brings us to another part
of being able to focus so over the years
um I've learned that sleep is the number
one thing to help my brain work and I
should probably make a video just about
sleep but that means taking naps uh or
sometimes I'll do like a you know a
biphasic sleep schedule um but whatever
it takes to get refreshed because when
you wake up you know and you have
yourself a cup of coffee maybe if that's
what helps you then you can get focused
on that so those are some of the things
like you know when it comes to sleep
make sure you get sleep because when
you're fresh and you're awake you're
going to be able to perform a lot better
um um and you know this idea that you
need to just sleep you you should just
power through and sleep is for wimps or
whatever is totally non-scientific
and we know that our brains need sleep
and any any professional will tell you
that if you're not getting regular sleep
you are not performing in fact the
biggest mistakes I've ever made on the
job have been when I had not enough
sleep and then I would wake up like what
the hell did I do I had to take it back
sometimes um when it was code related
but you know if you're doing an
operational thing some of those like
late night you know we have to you know
Save the Planet kind of things those
those things a lot of times were bad in
fact one time we had a guy fall asleep
on a conference call true story we were
on this bridge call and one of the guys
it was something like 3 or 4:00 a.m. and
he started snoring on the
phone and we're like we were like Kent
Kent wake up he's like nobody could hear
anything we could nobody could hear
anything he was just totally going up
and we're like we're like just just hang
the phone up and go take a nap because
he was no good to us in fact he was
distracting everybody else so so it is
true that you can you know maintain
Focus for a certain point by just
pushing through or whatever but for the
most part you're going to need some
sleep so remove distractions make sure
you get enough enough sleep um and
sometimes and then there's a question of
music right so everybody knows that I'm
a huge fan of Music um I use music of
all kinds some people use have I mean
whatever music works for you I'm not
here to judge what music it is but
that's you know another way for you to
maintain focus is put the headphones on
um or not you know or just have ambient
music around or really exciting music or
uh there is some science to suggest that
mixing your music is better for your
brain than keeping it all chill or all
really intense um so so if you like like
in my hacker chill playlist you'll see
I'll have like a lot of chill music and
then I'll have like something that's
like kind of fast every once in a while
and it will kind of wake me up and get
me back in and then then I'll go back to
the chill stuff um yoga monstas and that
kind of thing so music is a big is a big
way to to stay focused um you know I
don't we could talk about all the
different know chemical ways to stay
focused um you know including Aderall
I've never done Aderall I don't have any
intention of doing it I know a lot of
hackers do Aderall I know a lot of um
competitive programmers do Aderall I
know a lot of Gamers do Aderall um I
still don't everybody every time I even
mention it somebody comes up with a
story in my community they're like oh my
God no no no no no no don't you don't
want to do that because they've spent
their life trying to detox and recover
from from addiction because of Aderall
so you know you know my my buddy who
went to med school he made it into med
school very good med school actually and
did never he never did cocaine or any of
these things now coffee on the other
hand I I do have quite a few copies I I
I don't talk about that but so there are
chemical ways for you to to to do that
there is actually something also I
wanted to make a video about this
probably by itself it's called the
Balmer
Peak and I had be careful talking about
it because then somebody's going to
inevitably abuse the idea the Balmer
Peak is this sort of pseudo science idea
that was emitted by Steve Balmer monkey
boy Balmer who was famous for getting
really high on cocaine before he did the
monkey boy Balmer video which we'll play
another day developers developers
developers and but at Microsoft where he
was there he had this theory that if you
were just a little bit drunk but not all
the way drunk that that could settle
your brain down and allow you to focus
and I got to tell you up it works uh the
problem is is it's almost impossible to
maintain because you have to have a a
certain level and if you go past that
level of of
drunkenness uh you know you're yeah if
you go past that level of drunkenness
then you end up um unable to function
right and then if you're not there
you're not there enough just not quite
enough so be really careful with the
bmer pink there's there's there are a
bunch of jokes related to the bmer peak
um and I'll let you guys go find all
those um so when it comes to chemical
you know induc changes to your to help
you focus um again I'm not here to judge
you but but beware of those because they
don't always come I mean coffee for
example um for me it's been espresso if
I do if I chug back a lot of the other
coffee I get a really acidic stomach and
it it it's you know it get becomes
painful and stuff but espresso has the
exact amount of like caffeine and it's
you can get it pretty quickly it doesn't
impact your day you don't have to make a
whole pot and then you know if you need
another one you can the thing is though
if you overdo caffeine you'll know this
you drop it drops you down it drops you
later on um caffeine has
been totally totally um scientifically
Vindicated to produce performance in
endurance athletes you can go watch the
videos and look up the sides on that um
it has to be done 40 minutes before the
event though people think that they're
going to kick it at the end and they
take you know a caffeine gel and they
don't get their results until way after
they pass the Finish Line um so if
you're going to do the chemical thing to
help you focus you know that's you're
going to have to to think about that on
your own
um so those are all all ways for you to
consider um how to improve your focus um
but and I I think that you'll find
you're you're going to have your your
own ideas if you if you want to share
something that I may have missed in the
in the chat I do feel like I'm missing
some of my methods um uh of of finding
Focus myself but um uh maybe that's
because I haven't had enough copy I
don't know